Contact

sakunthala.tech@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sakunthalaramagounder (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

AngularJS Express.js Node.js

Sakunthala Ramagounder

Full Stack Developer at Self Employed

Salem, Tamil Nadu, India

Summary

An accomplished Telecom professional with 16+ years of experience in Software Management,

Design and creation of scalable software with clean, functional code on the front- and back-end as a Full stack developer.

Design and Development in various technologies like WiMax, LTE, SS7, GSM and GPRS using Java Technologies.

Handled IAM (Identity and Access Management) product development activities.

Possess extensive exposure in Network and Element Management System (EMS/NMS) and Telecom domains.

SDLC proficiency in mapping business requirements, technical documentation, application design, development, integration, testing and troubleshooting for EMS/NMS solutions.

Felicitated with 'Valuable Team Player' reward for commitment and dedication.

Experience

Self Employed Full Stack Developer November 2022 - Present (3 months) Salem, Tamil Nadu, India

Full Stack (MEAN) developer. Developing Web applications with MEAN stack

SENNOVATE INFOTECH (INDIA) PRIVATE LIMITED

Product Development Manager March 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Salem, Tamil Nadu, India

Handled IAM (Identity and Access Management) product development activities.

Tech Mahindra
Technical Architect
April 2007 - June 2015 (8 years 3 months)
Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Network Provisioning for Cisco Prime Fulfillment.

The Cisco Prime Provisioning is software that enables Service Providers to provision Layer2 and Layer3 parameters for their network devices. It supports Cisco and Non-Cisco devices to provision various networking services.

Tech Mahindra (R & D Services) Ltd. Senior Software Engineer April 2004 - March 2007 (3 years) Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

The CMS (Configuration Management System) enables Service Providers to use one common platform to manage Customer Premise Devices (CPE) from a central location using TR069 interface. The CMS application provides a web user interface that allows administrators to perform management functions easily. It has the following capabilities for managing collections of CPEs, Auto-configuration and dynamic service provisioning Software/firmware image management Software module management Status and performance monitoring Diagnostics

Axes Technologies (I) Pvt Ltd Software Engineer September 2001 - March 2004 (2 years 7 months) Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

The NMS(Network Management System) product is a Next Generation Java Based product, built from WebNMS platform, for managing one or more switches configured in a Host-Remote network topology. The NMS would allow performing all the FCAPS functionalities

Convergelabs Software Technologies Ltd,. Software Engineer

October 2000 - August 2001 (11 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Design and implementation of LSPU. It is a module, which contains databases HLR, VLR and EIR for a GSM network.

Education

Kongu Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (August 1996 - March 2000)

University of Madras

M.Sc, Psychology · (June 2017 - May 2019)

Kongu Engineering College

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (August 1996 - March 2000)